#### **Darren Atherton**

Email: darren.a.atherton@gmail.com

Website: http://darrenatherton.co.uk GitHub: http://github.com/DarrenAtherton49

**LinkedIn:** http://www.linkedin.com/in/darrenatherton

A motivated, goal-driven Android developer with a strong academic background and several years of experience. I am passionate about building apps with an excellent user experience, grounded in clean, well-architected and testable code whilst keeping myself up-to-date with the latest developments in open-source Android software.

### Skills

### Android Development

- Android Framework/Studio, Java, Kotlin (in progress), clean (layered) architecture/SOLID principles, modern design patterns (MVP/MVVM), test-driven development (UI and unit testing), reactive programming (RxJava), material design, XML layout design, Gradle build process, dependency injection, performance profiling and optimisation (via monitor, Traceview, hierarchy viewer and XML layout analysis), JSON/XML parsing, REST API consumption and Google Play store submission process.
- Libraries/technologies used Support libraries, AppCompat, Retrofit 2/OkHttp, Glide/Picasso, Butterknife, Dagger 2, LeakCanary, RxJava/RxAndroid, Espresso and Appium (UI testing), JUnit 4 (presenter/model testing), Timber, Icepick, FindBugs-IDEA, JSON (Gson), XML and MySQL.

#### Workflow/Process

Git/SVN, Jenkins, Jira, Trello, MeisterTask, Slack.

# General

- Experienced in working independently and as part of various-sized teams.
- Experienced in troubleshooting and problem-solving.
- Excellent time-management skills developed during the organisation of my own working hours during PhD study.
- Full UK driving license.

# Work Experience

Android Developer at Eagle Eye Solutions

Nov 2015 - present

- Eagle Eye is a SaaS platform that validates and redeems digital promotions in real-time for the grocery, retail and hospitality industries. As an Android developer, I am responsible for developing the native Android white label application which facilitates the redemption of promotions, offers and rewards by interacting with the platform. The applications I have developed during this time include Toby Carvery, Green Card Pubs, Nicholson's, All Bar One and Harvester using the technologies described in the skills section above.
- Software Engineer at Momote (MyMobileWorkers)

Jul 2013 - Aug 2014

- MyMobileWorkers provides off-the-shelf mobile workforce management software offering features such as field service management, proof of delivery support and asset tracking. As a software developer for MyMobileWorkers, I was responsible for working on multiple systems:
  - 1. A web and mobile API, developed with Java EE and MySQL and deployed to Glassfish Server, which served as an integration point for companies through which they had full CRUD access to their field service data via web requests and the MyMobileWorkers Android application.
  - 2. An Android application developed using the native Android Framework, which is the primary component of the MyMobileWorkers field service solution.

- Lab Demonstrator (Computer Science) at University of Liverpool
- Oct 2014 July 2015
- Modules taught: COMP282 (Advanced Object-Oriented C Languages) and COMP102 (Introduction to Databases).
- This role involved giving practical code demonstrations to students and assisting them with their lab solutions, as well as marking formal code submissions and giving feedback. The lab classes undertaken involved teaching MySQL, Objective-C and C++.

# Education

PhD Computer Science, University of Liverpool

2014 - 2015

- Status: Withdrawn from studies with 1 year completed successfully.
- Work undertaken: 'Combining Persuasive Technology and Motivation Theories for Children's Language Development'. This project is a continuation of my undergraduate dissertation, attempting to combine notions from artificial intelligence, persuasive technology and behaviour change/motivation theories to develop dynamic, intelligent motivational applications for the purpose of motivating parents to help their young children acquire language. During this time, I undertook this research as a member of the Agent ART research group and in the context of the International Centre for Language and Communicative Development (LuCiD). For this project, I gained a great amount of knowledge on argument and computation theory, artificial intelligence, user modelling, persuasive/motivational technologies, behavioural theory and application interaction design. During this project I also gained important writing and communication skills, by submitting research material to peer-reviewed publication venues and giving corresponding presentations.
- BSc Computer Information Systems, University of Liverpool

2010 - 2013

- Award: First-class honours.
- Notable modules: Programming in Java (84%), Mobile Computing iOS (90%), Group Software Project (80%), Software Development Tools (87%), Multi-Agent Systems (90%), Technologies for E-Commerce (95%) and Experimental Methods in Computing (87%).
- Dissertation: 'A Motivational Interface to a Personalised Tool to Monitor Children's Language Development'. This project involved research into persuasive technology with a focus on behaviour change. Following this, I implemented an application which allowed parents to track their child's language development and milestones on a customisable timeline, whilst receiving personalised information about their child. The application was implemented natively on iOS with Objective-C in Xcode, and the corresponding web server was implemented using PHP with the database using MySQL.
- BTEC National Diploma for IT Practitioners, Liverpool Community College

2008 - 2010

- Award: Distinction, Distinction, Distinction.
- GCSE, Halewood College

2002 - 2007

• Award: 9 GCSE's graded A-C, including Mathematics and English.

## **Awards and Activities**

- Awarded an attainment Scholarship each year for continuous achievement throughout my undergraduate degree Department of Computer Science, University of Liverpool (2010 11, 2011 12, 2012 13).
- Awarded a EPSRC Doctoral Training Studentship for the duration of my PhD Department of Computer Science, University of Liverpool (2014 2015).
- Published a two-page abstract and gave a corresponding 20-minute talk on 'Personalising Motivation: Combining Motivation Theories and Persuasive Technology for Children's Language Development' Doctoral Consortium, Persuasive Conference 2015, Chicago, Illinois.